what computer should you get and or
computer should you get uh this is a big
question it came about people were
asking me this question is a followup to
well I have my cka my certified
kubernetes administrator and you're
telling me I should make a lab but I
don't have money to make a lab and the
question is what where do you get
computers what kind of computers would
you recommend for building out your lab
at home so I'm going to tell you I'm
going to share with you the computers
that I Bo to build up my lab and why I
think that it's not as big an expense as
you might think it is you are going to
need a switch of some kind and I don't
want to go through all the things you're
going to need here that's part of the
learning processes for you to figure out
what stuff you actually need but if you
look at my screen um you can see the
core piece of this so so in order to do
any kind of um lab environment you need
to have more than one computer and those
computers need to be actual computers
they need to be significant they need to
be fast and they need to have pretty
fast um SSD solid state drives in order
to simulate things like sccd and these
you know really really low latency um
things you need at home um these Dell
Optiplex are some of the best ones you
can get these are refurbished and I got
these for $150 each now consider for a
side this one was $127 they've gone even
down even farther considering that these
that these computers are you know the
the specs on these computers is is
amazing um in fact let's look at it so
it's got It's got a quad core i5 you
don't need more than this you're doing
simulations of nodes you don't need a
don't think about gaming and all that
stuff that's not what you're doing
you're just building out Hardware nodes
that have other fundamental requirements
and what are those requirements they
need to be cheap they need to be small
so they fit in wherever you're going to
put them and that means they don't take
a lot of power they need to have uh
really solid networking capabilities and
they need to be able to pixie boot that
means they need to be able to be booted
from the network so that you can
practice reimaging things by just
rebooting them and having them pull down
their their operating system from the
network and they need to what's called
Network boot um and and that's it and so
they don't need a lot of dis space uh in
fact the dis space you're going to be
adding is probably going to be coming in
another space so who needs a computer
like this and when should you get one if
you are just starting out and this
you're watching this video because
you're doing the beginner boost and you
want to get good and you don't want to I
mean you may have considered saving up
your money for a good Mac laptop for
your own personal use but you want to
server you can run at home or two or
four and you want to be able to run
those doing different things and
practice networking and and all of the
great things that you need to do to be
able to become a real good uh
infrastructure engineer then this is
this this is the way to go these these
are the things to get don't people buy
raspberry pies and orange pies and
things like that to try to replace an
actual computer they're good computers
and they have some pretty interesting
racks we can put them all in there but
they're in my opinion they're a bit too
small to kind of do this kind of thing
so you know 256 SSD is pretty damn good
uh 3.1 GHz 16 gabt of ram you're not
getting these machines to be able to
carve them up into virtual machines
right you're getting them so that you
can put a whole bunch of them in a stack
uh and you know practice your networking
and your VLAN setup and and you know
you're setting up cni for kubernetes
that's why you're getting it um if if
you have no other decision to make than
what is my first computer that I'm going
to buy um and you're you know you
already have a computer you're using to
watch this video uh probably a Mac or
Windows machine then I think probably
your first purchase should be a computer
like this somebody might also say well
Dell sucks Dell sucks for Toops but Del
for servers is really good so um this is
the first kind of computer I suggest
everyone get um for their server room
and one of the reasons it's nice because
it doesn't have a screen that means
you're going to need to learn how to use
a remote screen you're going to have to
learn how to SSH into it all the great
things that you need so your the bur
cheapest piece of your lab might be one
or two you know an Optiplex an oplex
like this and then later if you want to
splurge a little bit more money you
might want to get a tower that you can
practice just carving up into virtual
machines which is you know something you
would get later a lot of people would
recommend to you that you get that first
because you know you can put whatever
you want on there to chop it up into
multiple little tiny machines but the
truth of the matter is you still need
something to run a Minecraft server on
for fun a running Linux to get your
Linux skills good or whatever and one of
these D Optiplex is really great for
that so that's my recommendation take
that to heart make your own decisions
and we'll talk to you later